<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="configuration.xsl"?>

<configuration>
  
 <property>
    <name>content</name>
    <description>This is the jinja template for /etc/sssd.conf file</description>
    <value>
    
# This section defines the global parameters for the service
[sssd]
config_file_version = 2

# domains: The 'domains' parameter doubles as a mnemonic for an 'identity provider', and later on the actual AD domain we're connecting to
domains = {{domain}}

# services: The 'services' I require. Note that I only want the 'nss' service (users/groups lookup). Don't want PAM, especially on the Master/Data nodes
services = nss

# [nss]: This is where we configure the NSS service
[nss]
# Filter out the users and groups that we don't want Hadoop to see. Not important. But feel free to add more if you like.
filter_groups = root
filter_users = root

reconnection_retries = 3
entry_cache_timeout = 300
entry_cache_nowait_percentage = 75

# debug levels 5 to 7 seem to be appropriate while testing. I suggest starting with level five.
debug_level = 5

# This is where we define the properties of this particular Identity Provider (AD LDAP instance running on 'hwxincdc.cloud.hortonworks.com')
[domain/{{domain}}]

fallback_homedir = /home/%u

# id_provider: Active Directory supports both "ad" (must create Kerberos SPNs) or "ldap" (can specify simple password later on).
id_provider = ldap

# Because I've specified 'ldap', I can get away with a simple password to authenticate. Tip: Don't try to type DNs, instead copy/paste them from a suitable LDAP Browing tool

ldap_default_bind_dn = {{bind_dn}}
ldap_default_authtok_type = password
ldap_default_authtok = {{bind_password}} 

# auth_provider: I don't want authentication, and especially not SSH access to my Hadoop master/data nodes 
auth_provider = none

#chpass_provider/access_provider: Don't need/don't care
#chpass_provider = 
#access_provider = 
min_id = 1000

#ad_domain = (No need to define it, because it takes it from [domain/*Name*] above)
#ad_domain =

# The AD server hosting the KDC service
ad_server = {{ldap_hostname}}

# ad_hostname: When authenticating via Kerberos, SSSD will automatically use the FQDN of *this* host. Try leaving it blank. But if your host can't figure out it's FQDN (you'll know from the logs), you can use this parameter to explicitly set it
# ad_hostname = {{ldap_hostname}}

# ldap_uri: The AD server hosting the LDAP service. 
# LDAP (plain text or TLS) and SSL (ldaps://) is also supported, but you'll need to configure the CA certifcate within OpenSSL
ldap_uri = {{ldap_protocol}}://{{ldap_hostname}}

# ldap_schema: Instructs SSSD on which LDAP attributes to use to derive the user/group memberships 
ldap_schema = ad

# for SID-UID mapping: Instructs SSSD to handle the complex Domain SID group mappings automatically 
ldap_id_mapping = True

# Enable the cache on this host (gentler on the AD servers). Delete it if you need to from /var/lib/sss/db/*
cache_credentials = true

# performance
ldap_referrals = false


    </value>
  </property>
  
        
</configuration>